Vue's component architecture allows us to build our user interface into components
Vue的组件架构允许我们将用户界面构建到组件中
which beautifully organize our business logic and our presentation layer
它很好地组织了我们的业务逻辑和视图层
However
但是
there are some instances where one component has some html
在某些情况下，某些组件有一些html
that needs to get rendered in an alternative location
它需要在另一个位置呈现
Why might you want to do this
为什么你要这么做
well Some components like models with fixed or absolute
一些组件像固定的或绝对的模型
positioning and z index may need to be placed right before the body tag
可能需要在body标签之前放置positioning和zindex
and There's no best practice on how to do this
关于如何做到这一点并没有最好的实践
Also
另外
if our view application is running on a small part of our web page
如果我们视图应用程序在网页的一小部分上运行
we might want to move some of that template code out of our Vue at
我们可能需要将一些模板代码移出我们的Vue
and Again, there's no easy way to do this
没有简单的方法
Luckily, Vue3.0 now has a teleport component
幸运的是，Vue3.0现在有一个传送组件
This was previously called portal
这以前被称为portal
but the name was changed to teleport as to not conflict to a
但是这个名字被改成teleport
future version of html where they might have a tag called portal
因为这样可以不与未来版本的html冲突,有一个标签叫做portal
Teleport allows us to specify template html we can send to another part of the DOM
Teleport允许我们指定模板html，我们可以将其发送到DOM的另一部分
Let's jump into a real simple example
让我们来看看一个简单的例子
First, inside of our public index that html
首先，在我们的public/index.html
right under where our application is rendered
这里就是我们的应用被渲染的地方
i've added an end of body div
我加了一个div在body的后面
We want to teleport some template code here
我想传送一些代码在这里
then inside of our app Vue, inside our template
在Vue APP内部，在模板内
We'll write teleport to end of body
需要写
We'll specify the text We want to teleport
我们会指定我们想要传送的文本
This should be the end
内容是"This should be the end"
and Then we'll write this should be the Top
这个是"This should be the top"
If this works right, this should be the end
如果能成功，"this should be the end"
Should be teleport it out of our Vue application
应该将其传送到Vue应用程序到这个div
And into this div
Actually putting it at the end of our page
实际上把它放在我们页面的末尾
and If we look in a browser, we see that indeed
如果我们在浏览器中看到，我们确实看到了
it is teleportation
被传送到页面的末尾
to the end
In order to use the teleport component
为了使用teleport 组件
you need to define a "to" attribute which takes a valid DOM query selector
你需要定义一个"to"属性,接收一个Dom选择器
In our case, we're using the ID
在我们的案例里，我们用的是ID选择器
but we could also be using a class like so
但是我们也可以使用类选择器
or a data collector with square brackets
或具有方括号的data自定义选择器
In this case, our div would look like this
在这种情况下，我们分区是这样的
In case you're not familiar with the data attribute
以防你不熟悉这个data属性
Or this could even be a dynamic property by adding the colon
甚至可以是添加冒号的动态属性
models and Popup often stay hidden until they displayed on the screen
models和Popup往往隐藏，直到他们显示在屏幕上
This is why teleport has a disabled attribute
这就是为什么传送有一个disabled的属性
and When it's true, the contents can stay
如果是true，里面的东西可以保留下来
inside the component
在组件里面
And when it's false, it'll be teleport to the destination you specify
当它是false，它会被传送到你指定的地方
Let's update our code and try this
让我们更新我们的代码并尝试一下
We'll start by specifying a show text reactive property which defaults to false
我们将首先指定一个showText 响应式属性，该属性默认为false
Then back in our previous code
回到我们之前的代码
this will be disabled when showText is false
当显示文本为false时，showText将被禁用
Then we'll create a button to toggle showText between true and false
然后我们将创建一个按钮来切换showText的值
Now
现在
our code is either insider component or is teleport outside the component when it's not disabled
我们的代码要么是内部组件，要么在组件未禁用时传送到组件外
and If we look inside devTools
如果我们看里面的devTools的内部
we can see our code inside a template
我们可以在模板中看到我们的代码
and Then once we toggle it
一旦我们切换它
we can see it teleported into the end of body div
我们可以看到它被传送到body的末尾
into the end of the body
一直延伸到身体的末端
and If we toggle it back
如果我们把它切回去
we see it back inside
我们在里面看到
of our component
又回到了组件内部
One killer feature of teleport is that it reuses
传送的一个致命特性是它可以重复使用
the DOM elements
DOM元素
so State is preserved
因此数据得以保存
We can see this if we place a video inside of our teleport component
如果我们把video放在teleport组件里面，
so Now we can see, as we toggle this video
现在我们可以看到，当我们切换这个video
the state is preserved
数据被保存
Let's watch that one more time
我们再看一遍
If the content we had inside teleport was a modal
如果我们传送的内容是模态框
we wouldn't want to display it until it was teleport
在传送之前我们是不想展示的
and not disabled
直到他呗传送或者disabled为false的时候
so How would we hide the text
那么我们如何隐藏文本
When teleport is disabled
当teleport被禁用时
One way we can do this
一种我们能做到的方法
is simply by using a v-if with showText
是简单的通过v-if来控制showText
So now it's only gonna show this should be the end
所以现在只能展示"this should be the end"
When showText is true
当showText为true
In this case, only when it's teleported
在这种情况下，只有当它被传送时才会这样展示
When I first saw this feature, I started to wonder
当我第一次看到这个特性时，我开始怀疑
what happens if we teleport
如果我们传送
two different things
两样不同的东西
To the same location. Does it still work
去同一个地方。 它还能用吗
Let's give it a try
让我们试一试
I'm gonna make some room in my code
我要在我的代码中腾出一些空间
I'll add a new reactive property called show text two
我将添加一个新的响应式属性，称为showText2
I'll create a new teleport component
我将创建一个新的传送组件
which uses show text two and says this should be at the end too
它使用showText2内容是"this should be at the end too"
and then I'll create another button to toggle it
然后我会创建另一个按钮来切换它
Let's take a look at what this does
我们来看看这个能做什么
It's properly appending and removing
这是正确的追加和删除
the DOM nodes from the end of our page
来控制页面末尾开始的DOM节点
As you can see
如你所见
the teleport component and vue3.0 provides you a powerful way to write component template code
teleport 组件和vue3.0为您提供了一种编写组件模板代码的强大方法
which gets teleport it to other parts of your application
用来传送到应用程序的其他部分